A Finding Aid to the Sidney Janis Gallery Exhibition Catalogs, 1951-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.sidnjani
Archives of American Art
Sidney Janis Gallery exhibition catalogs
1951-1998
AAA.sidnjani
Archives of American Art
2.8 Linear feet
The Sidney Janis Gallery exhibition catalogs measure 2.8 linear feet and date from 1951 to 1998. Found here is a complete set of catalogs published by the New York gallery.
Janis, Sidney, 1896-1989
Sidney Janis Gallery
Arrangement note
This collection has been arranged into one series.
Series 1: Exhibition Catalogs, 1951-1998 (Boxes 1-7; 2.8 linear feet)
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The collection was donated in 1999 by Carroll Janis, son of Sidney Janis.
Related Archival Materials note
Also found at the Archives of American Art are two oral history interviews with Sidney Janis. One interview conducted March 21-September 26, 1972, by Paul Cummings, and one interview conducted on October 15 and November 18, 1981, by Avis Berman.
Biographical/Historical note
Sidney Janis Gallery (est. 1948-1999) was an art gallery in New York, N.Y., specializing in contemporary avant-garde art. Sidney Janis opened the gallery with his wife Harriet at 15 E. 57th Street in Manhattan. The gallery became a leading exhibitor of Pop art after the groundbreaking exhibition New Realists in 1962. The gallery moved to 110 W. 57th Street in the 1980s, and after Janis's death in 1989 the gallery was directed by his son Carroll Janis.
Scope and Contents note
The Sidney Janis Gallery exhibition catalogs measure 2.8 linear feet and date from 1951 to 1998. Found here is a complete set of catalogs published by the New York gallery.
Researchers should note that this collection only includes published catalogs and not related exhibition documentation. The gallery did not publish a catalog for every exhibition, especially during the early years of the gallery's operation.
Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York; Exhibition catalogs
- Exhibition Catalogs, 1951-1998; Series 1; 2.8 Linear feet Boxes 1-7
  Scope and Contents note
  Found here are a complete set of exhibition catalogs published by the Sidney Janis Gallery.
  Arrangement note
  Catalogs are arranged chronologically.
  - Henri Rousseau (November 5-December 22), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 5 Years of Janis (September 29-October 31), 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Futurism (March 22-May 1), 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 15 Years of Jackson Pollock (November 28-December 31), 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cubism, 1910-1912 (January 3-February 4), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Leger Major Themes (January 2-February 2), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fautrier (February 4-March 2), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jawlensky (March 4-30), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 8 Americans (April 4-April 20), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mondrian (September 30-November 2), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gorky (December 2-28), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tapestries (April 21-May 17), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - X Years of Janis (September 29-November 1), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Jackson Pollock (November 3-29), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 8 American Painters (January 5-31), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 75 Collages by Schwitters (February 2-March 7), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Late Drawings by Gorky (September 28-October 24), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Guston (December 28-January 23), 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Arp & Mondrian (January 25-March 5), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kline (March 7-April 2), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 9 American Painters (April 4-April 23), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - F. Leger (December 5-January 7), 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Robert Motherwell (April 10-May 6), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 10 American Painters (May 8-June 3), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Albers (October 2-28), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Paintings and Sculpture from the Gallery Collection (October 30-December 2), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Piet Mondrian (January 2-February 4), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Paintings by Arshile Gorky (February 5-March 3), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 10 American Painters (May 7-June 2), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Adolph Gottlieb (October 1-27), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New Realists (November 1-December 1), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Robert Motherwell (December 4-29), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Jim Dine (February 4-March 2), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Sculpture by Jean Arp (April 29-May 25), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 11 Abstract Expressionist Painters (October 7-November 2), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Piet Mondrian (November 4-30), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Memorial Exhibition Kline (December 3-28), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Classic Spirit in 20th Century Art (February 4-29), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Claes Oldenburg (April 7-May 2), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Albers Homage to the Square (September 28-October 24), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 3 Generations (November 24-December 26), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Arman (December 29-January 27), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Abstract Tromp L'Oeil (January 26-February 27), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Morris Hirschfield, 1972-1945 (March 2-April 3), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ellsworth Kelly (April 6-May 1), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Recent Work by Arman, Dine, Fahstrom, Marisol, Oldenburg, Segal (May 5-31), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - George Segal (October 4-30), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Anuszkiewicz (November 3-27), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Vasarely (January 5-February 5), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Oldenburg (March 9-April 2), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Wesselmann (May 10-June 4), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Erotic Art (October 3-29), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Jim Dine (November 1-26), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Steinberg (November 29-December 24), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 2 Generations: Picasso-Pollock (January 3-27), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Oyvind Fahlstrom (February 1-25), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ellsworth Kelly (March 1-25), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Segal (March 29-April 22), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Claes Oldenburg (April 26-May 27), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Anuszkiewicz (October 2-25), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Marisol (November 1-30), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Homage to Marilyn Monroe (December 6-30), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Vasarely (January 8-February 3), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Tom Wesselmann (February 6-March 2), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Jean Arp (March 6-April 6), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ellsworth Kelly (October 7-November 2), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Giacometti and Dubuffet (November 6-30), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - George Segal (December 4-January 4), 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Selected Works by 20th Century Artists (January 8-February 1), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Konrad Klapheck (February 5-March 1), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Oyvind Fahlstrom (March 5-29), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Vasarely (October 6-November 1), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Domenico Gnoli (December 3-27), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - String and Rope (January 7-31), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - The High Kitsch of Eilshemius (March 11-April 4), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Wesselmann (April 8-May 2), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - George Segal (May 6-29), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Albers (October 5-31), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Claes Oldenburg (November 4-28), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 7 Artists (December 4-31), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Richard Anuszkiewicz (February 10-March 6), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Fahlstrom (March 17-April 10), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - An Arp Garden of Marbles and Bronzes (October 4-30), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Ellsworth Kelly (November 3-27), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Jann Haworth (December 2-31), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Sharp-Focus Realism (January 6-February 5), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Colossal Scale (March 9-April 1), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Vasarely (April), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Los Angeles '72 (May 11-June 3), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - de Kooning (October 4-November 4), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Wesselmann (November 8-December 2), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Segal (January 11-February 3), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Saul Steinberg (February 7-March 3), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Richard Anuszkiewicz (March 7-31), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Oyvind Fahlstrom (April 4-28), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Marisol (May 3-31), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 25 Years of Janis (October 2-November 3), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Erotic Art of Bellmer (January 10-February 2), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Mondrian (February 7-March 9), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 25 Years of Janis Part 2 (March 13-April 13), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Wesselmann (April 20-May 25), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Segal (October 1-November 26), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Pistoletto (November 6-30), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Herbin (December 4-31), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Tom Blackwell (February 5-March 1), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Marisol (March 5-29), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Motorcycle by David Parrish (April 2-26), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Bridget Riley (April 30-May 31), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Giacometti (January 8-31), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Oyvind Fahlstrom (March 18-April 10), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Wesselmann (April 21-May 22), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Duane Michals (October 19-November 13), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Steinberg Cartoons (November 17-December 11), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - George Segal (January 26-February 26), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Yves Klein (March 3-April 2), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Less is More (April 7-May 7), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - J.Torres-Garcia (October 4-29), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Max Cole (November 3-26), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Magritte (December 1-31), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Walker Evans (January 6-February 4), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Richard Lindner (April 6-May 6), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bridget Riley (May 10-June 2), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Duane Michals (November 1-25), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - George Segal (November 30-December 30), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Americans and New York Photographs by Robert Frank (February 1-24), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Wesselmann (April 26-June 1), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Personalities and Places by Gisele Freund (December 6-January 5), 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Arp (January 10-February 16), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - P. Mondrian (February 21-March 29), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Seven Decades of Twentieth-Century Art (La Jolla Museum of Contemporary Art March 29-May 11, Santa Barbara Museum of Art June 6-August 10), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Gallery Moving Flier (October 1), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - George Segal (October 1-November 1), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Wesselmann (November 6-December 6), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Duane Michals (December 11-January 6), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Michael David Evolution of the Symbol (April 9-May 2), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 250 Photographs of Picasso by David Douglas Duncan (October 25-November 28), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Oyvind Fahlstrom, 1928-1976 (January 7-30), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Robert Mangold (March 4-27), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - George Segal (April 1-May 1), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Wesselmann (May 1-29), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - A Collaboration: Patsy Norvell & Robert Zakanitch (November 4-27), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Brancusi + Mondrian (December 2-31), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Duane Michals (January 13-February 5), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Gandy Brodie (March 10-April 2), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Valerie Jaudon (April 7-April 30), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Graffiti (December 1-31), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - American Women Artists Part I: 20th Century Pioneers (January 12-February 14), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - American Women Artists Part II: The Recent Generation (February 11-March 3), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Modern Expressionists (March 10-April 7), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - New Sculpture George Segal (April 14-May 12), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Albers (October 4-November 3), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - F. Leger (October 19-28), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Crash (November 8-December 1), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Early Mondrian (February 7-March 9), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 3 Graffiti Artists (March 14-April 6), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Valerie Jaudon (April 11-May 4), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Alberto Giacometti (Septmember 17-November 2), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Albers (February 1-March 1), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Crash! (March 13-April 12), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Yves Klein (April 19-May 31), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - George Segal (September 27-November 1), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Valerie Jaudon (November 6-29), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Katherine Porter (January 8-31), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - The Nature of Desire and Other Works Duane Michals (February 10-March 7), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Early 20th Century Masters (March 12-April 29), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Sculpture by Elie Nadelman (September 28-October 31), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Recent Tendencies in Black and White (December 3-24), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Mondrian (January 4-February 13), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - George Segal (April 30-June 4), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Arnold Newman (September 15-October 8), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Tom Wesselmann (October 15-November 19), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Crash (December 1-24), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 40th Anniversary (January 14-March 11), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - George Segal (March 18-April 22), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Marisol (April 29-June 3), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Albers (October 5-31), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Chillida (November 11-January 11), 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Zakanitch (February 1-24), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Valerie Jaudon (March 30-April 21), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Tom Wesselmann Steel Landscapes (April 28-June 2), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Jean Arp (October 3-November 10), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Classic Modernism Six Generations (November 15-December 23), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Who Framed Modern Art (January 10-February 16), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - R.M. Fischer (February 28-March 23), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Mondrian Flowers (March 28-April 27), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - George Segal (May 3-June 8), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Duane Michals Poetry and Tales (October 3-November 2), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Conceptual Abstraction (November 7-December 21), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 4 European Masters (January), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - A Mediterranean Installation (January-February), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Crash (March 5-28), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Herve di Rosa: Painter, Richard di Rosa: Sculptor (April), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - George Segal: Sculpture for FDR Memorial Washington, DC (May 1-June 6), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Duane Michals Paris Stories and Other Follies (September 17-October 10), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Tom Wesselmann (October 15-November 14), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 20th Century Masters on Paper (December 10-January 23), 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - George Segal (March 19-May 1), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Oyvind Fahlstrom ( October 7-November 6), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Albers (November 18-December 31), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - George Segal (March 31-April 30), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Christopher Wilmarth (February 18-March 25), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - George Segal (March 30-April 29), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Tom Wesselmann (May 4-June 10), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Images, Masks, and Models Peter Halley (November), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Valerie Jaudon (February 28-March 23), 1996 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Arman at Janis (March 29-April 27), 1996 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Wesselmann Paper Maquettes (March 30- May 4), 1996 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Sandro Chia (May 4-June 8), 1996 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Tom Wesselmann Abstract Paintings (September 19-October 26), 1996 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Masters at Janis (November 1-December 21), 1996 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Christian Eckart (February 14-March 8), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - George Segal Sculpture and Works on Paper (April 25-June 6), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Rona Pondick (September 27-October 25), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - American Self-Taughts (January 17-February 28), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - George Segal (March 7-April 4), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Tom Wesselmann New Paintings (May 16-June 13), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - What is Beauty? Questions Without Answers Duane Michals (November 17-December 24), undated (Box 7, Folder 35)